Inventory of the Paul B. Henze papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Horn of Africa File, 1959-2009 (Box 59-143)
  - Diaries, 1970-2006
    - 1998 February (Box-folder 69: 5)
      Ethiopia. Includes photographs of Henze with an unidentified official.
    - 1999 March-April (Box-folder 69: 6)
    - 2001 October-December (Box-folder 69: 7)
    - 2002 November-December (Box-folder 69: 8)
    - 2005 May-June (Box-folder 69: 9)
    - 2006 January-February (Box-folder 69: 10)
    - 2006 December and 2007 February-March (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - Speeches and writings, 1971-2009
    Includes correspondence related to publication.
    - Fragments, undated (Box-folder 70: 1)
    - "Comments on a British Draft Paper on the Future of Ethiopia,", 1971 March 5 (Box-folder 70: 2)
    - "Excursion to Lake Shalla,", 1972 February 18-21 (Box-folder 70: 3)
    - "Island Culture of Lake Zway,", 1973 (Box-folder 70: 4)
    - "Lake Zway and Its Islands,", 1973 (Box-folder 70: 5)
    - Research notes, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 70: 6)
    - Ethiopian Journeys, 1977 (Box-folder 70: 7-10)
    - "Return to Ethiopia,", 1977 September (Box-folder 70: 11)
    - Letter to the editor of The Middle East Review, 1978 Fall (Box-folder 70: 12)
    - "Northernmost Shoa,", 1979 (Box-folder 70: 13)
    - Paul Henze interview, 1979 (Box-folder 70: 14)
    - "American Policy Toward the Soviet Union,", 1979 July (Box-folder 70: 15)
    - "Axum and the Beginnings of Ethiopian Civilization,", 1980 November 4 (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - "A Communist Ethiopia?,", 1981 (Box-folder 71: 2)
    - Notes on Carter administration policy in the Horn of Africa, 1981 (Box-folder 71: 3)
    - "Letter from Addis Ababa,", 1981 February (Box-folder 71: 4)
    - Ethiopian investment reports, 1981 March (Box-folder 71: 5)
    - "To Reagan: Don't Blow It in the Horn of Africa,", 1981 April 3 (Box-folder 71: 6)
    - "Communism and Ethiopia,", 1981 May-June (Box-folder 71: 7)
    - "When Qaddafi Plays with the Horn,", 1981 October 16 (Box-folder 71: 8)
    - Book proposal on the 1974 Ethiopian revolution, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 9)
    - "How Stable Is Siad Barre's Regime?,", 1982 (Box-folder 71: 10)
    - "Getting a Grip on the Horn: The Soviet Union and the Horn of Africa, 1945-1982,", 1982 May (Box-folder 71: 11)
    - "Arming the Horn, 1960-1980,", 1982 July (Box-folder 71: 12-13)
    - "Ethiopia 1981: Impressions and Reflections,", 1982 August (Box-folder 71: 14)
    - "Russians and the Horn: Opportunism and the Long View,", 1982 August (Box-folder 71: 15)
    - "Sour U.S. Note on the Horn,", 1982 August 4 (Box-folder 71: 16)
    - "Getting a Grip on the Horn: The Emergence of the Soviet Presence and Future Prospects,", 1983 (Box-folder 71: 17)
    - "History and the Horn,", 1983 (Box-folder 71: 18)
    - Research notes, 1983 November 4-5 (Box-folder 71: 19)
    - Book reviews by Paul Henze, 1984 (Box-folder 72: 1)
    - "Economic Development of Ethiopia and Kenya, 1950-1975: An Essay in Comparison,", 1984 (Box-folder 72: 2)
    - "Tourism in Ethiopia: Observations and Recommendations,", 1984 (Box-folder 72: 3)
    - Book proposal on Ethiopian archaeology, 1984 January (Box-folder 72: 4)
    - "Revolutionary Ethiopia: Has It Been Transformed?,", 1984 March (Box-folder 72: 5)
    - "Ethiopia Marches to Marxist Drummer, but with Western Flair,", 1984 May 24 (Box-folder 72: 6)
    - "Ethiopia: From Ancient Empire to Revolutionary Socialism,", 1984 July (Box-folder 72: 7-8)
    - "Christian Brothers and Imperial Ambitions: A Survey of Russian Interest in Ethiopia and the Horn of Africa from the mid-19th Century through the Early Soviet Period,", 1984 October (Box-folder 72: 9-10)
    - "Getting a Handle on the Horn: How Can the United States Reassert Itself in this Important Region?,", 1984 November 9 (Box-folder 72: 11)
    - "A Study of the Economy of Revolutionary Ethiopia," research proposal, 1985 (Box-folder 72: 12)
    - "Communist Ethiopia: Is It Succeeding?,", 1985 January (Box-folder 72: 13)
    - "How Communist Is Mengistu's Ethiopia? Is It Irretrievably Lost to the West?,", 1985 January (Box-folder 72: 14)
    - "Marxism-Leninism in Ethiopia: Political Impasse and Economic Degradation,", 1985 June (Box-folder 72: 15)
    - "Dilemmas of the Horn,", 1985 July (Box-folder 73: 1)
    - Tourism articles on Lake Zway for Selamta, 1985 August (Box-folder 73: 2-3)
    - "Rebels and Separatists in Ethiopia: Regional Resistance to a Marxist Regime,", 1985 December (Box-folder 73: 4-5)
    - "Ethiopia: An Issue for the Summit's Agenda?,", 1986 (Box-folder 73: 6)
    - "Eritrea: The Endless War,", 1986 (Box-folder 73: 7)
    - "The Soviet Impact on African Political Dynamics,", 1986 (Box-folder 73: 8)
    - "Exploiting Famine-And Capitalizing on Western Generosity,", 1986 March (Box-folder 73: 9)
    - "Behind the Ethiopian Famine," three-part series for Encounter, 1986 June-October (Box-folder 73: 10-11)
    - Comments on Haile Selassie's Students by Randi Ronning Balsvik, 1986 June (Box-folder 73: 12)
    - "Ethiopia's Marxism Rests on Brutality,", 1986 September 15 (Box-folder 73: 13)
    - Illuminated Manuscripts of Lake Zway, 1986 October (Box-folder 73: 14)
    - "Flexible Opportunism: Three Essays Examining Soviet Strategy as Applied to Egypt, the Nile Valley and the Horn of Africa,", 1986 December (Box-folder 73: 15)
    - "Meeting with Goshu Wolde,", 1986 December 12 (Box-folder 73: 16)
    - "Lake Zway: Southern Christian Outpost and Repository of Medieval Ethiopian Art,", 1987 January 4 (Box-folder 74: 1)
    - "When the NSC Worked,", 1987 January 8 (Box-folder 74: 2)
    - "Eritrea in 1987: Diary of a Three Day Visit in the Late Derg Era," (Box-folder 74: 3)
    - "Ethiopia Between Famines,", 1987 (Box-folder 74: 4-6)
    - Flexible Persistence over Four Decades: The USSR and the Horn of Africa, 1987 April (Box-folder 74: 7)
    - "Is There Hope for the Horn? Reflections on the Political and Economic Impasse of the Region,", 1987 May (Box-folder 74: 8)
    - Comments on Christopher Clapham's book manuscript, 1987 June (Box-folder 74: 9)
    - "Arms in the Horn of Africa, 1980 to 1985, with Statistics on Economic Growth and Social Services,", 1987 October (Box-folder 74: 10)
    - "Ethiopia 1987: Contrasts and Contradictions,", 1987 October (Box-folder 74: 11)
    - "Eritrea: The Dilemmas of Marxism,", 1987 October (Box-folder 74: 12)
    - Statements on Ethiopia to U.S. House of Representatives Subcommittees on Human Rights and African Affairs, 1987 October 21 (Box-folder 74: 13, Box-folder 75: 1)
    - "Ethiopia: Crisis of a Marxist Economy (Analysis and Text of a Soviet Report),", 1987 December (Box-folder 75: 2)
    - "Decline of the Horn and the Fallacy of Superpower Rivalry,", 1988 (Box-folder 75: 3)
    - "Ethnic Strains and Regional Conflict in Ethiopia,", 1988 (Box-folder 75: 4)
    - "Soviet Impact on African Political Dynamics,", 1988 (Box-folder 75: 5)
    - "A Challenging Decade: The Economic Development of Ethiopia and Kenya, 1975-1984,", 1988 May (Box-folder 75: 6)
    - Comments on Robert G. Patman's dissertation, 1988 May (Box-folder 75: 7)
    - "Is There Hope for the Horn of Africa?,", 1988 June (Box-folder 75: 8-9)
    - "Comments on 'Unity of the Proletariat,'", 1988 October 27 (Box-folder 75: 10)
    - "The Russians in Egypt: Key to the Arab World,", 1989 (Box-folder 75: 11)
    - "The Strategic Long View: The Nile Valley and the Horn of Africa,", 1989 (Box-folder 75: 12)
    - "Ethiopia's Economic Prospects for the 1990s,", 1989 February (Box-folder 75: 13)
    - Contrasts in African Development: The Economies of Kenya and Ethiopia, 1975-1984, 1989 April (Box-folder 75: 14)
    - "The Ethiopian Revolution: Mythology and History,", 1989 July (Box-folder 75: 15)
    - Bibliography of Henze's writings on Ethiopia and the Horn of Africa, 1989 August (Box-folder 75: 16)
    - "Eritrean Options and Ethiopia's Future,", 1989 September (Box-folder 75: 17)
    - Commentary on Steven R. David's draft chapter on the Horn of Africa, 1989 November (Box-folder 75: 18)
    - "Ethiopia in Early 1989: Deepening Crisis,", 1989 November (Box-folder 75: 19)
    - "Mengistu's Ethiopian Marxist State in Terminal Crisis: How Long Can It Survive? What Will Be Its Legacy?,", 1989 December (Box-folder 75: 20)
    - "Marxist Disaster and Cultural Survival in Ethiopia: Books from the 1980s,", 1990 (Box-folder 76: 1)
    - "Restoring Peace and Progress to the Horn of Africa,", 1990 (Box-folder 76: 2)
    - "Three Decades of Arms for the Horn of Africa: A Statistical Analysis,", 1990 (Box-folder 76: 3)
    - Book prospectus on the Ethiopian economy, 1990 January (Box-folder 76: 4)
    - "Public Relations for Ethiopia,", 1990 January (Box-folder 76: 5)
    - "The Unique Role of the VOA's Amharic Service,", 1990 January (Box-folder 76: 6)
    - Statements to the U.S. Congress on Ethiopia, 1990 February 27-28 (Box-folder 76: 7)
    - "Ethiopia and the Challenge of Liberation,", 1990 March 10 (Box-folder 76: 8)
    - "Ethiopia: Environment, War and Development," answers to questions from the Joint Economic Committee, U.S. Congress, 1990 March 15 (Box-folder 76: 9)
    - "Glasnost about Building Socialism in Ethiopia: Analysis of a Critical Soviet Article,", 1990 April (Box-folder 76: 10)
    - "The Tigre People's Liberation Front: Conversations with Meles Zenawi," "The Tigre People's Liberation Front: Conversations with Meles Zenawi,", 1990 April (Box-folder 76: 11)
    - Letter to the editor of The Christian Science Monitor, 1990 April 12 (Box-folder 76: 12)
    - "Communist Collapse in Ethiopia,", 1990 July (Box-folder 76: 13)
    - "Situation of the TPLF/ERPDF as of Mid-1990: Conversation with Berhane Gebre Christos,", 1990 July 5 (Box-folder 76: 14)
    - "Oromo Tomb Architecture and Art,", 1990 September (Box-folder 76: 15)
    - "The United States and the Horn of Africa: History and Current Challenge,", 1990 October (Box-folder 76: 16)
    - "Eritrea: The Economic Challenge,", 1990 November (Box-folder 76: 17)
    - "Economic Dimensions of Federalism in the Horn of Africa,", 1990 December (Box-folder 76: 18)
    - "Ethiopia Notes 1990: Economic Discussions and Meeting with Mengistu,", 1990 December (Box-folder 76: 19)
    - "End and Beginning in Ethiopia,", 1991 (Box-folder 77: 1)
    - "Ethiopia in 1991: Peace Through Struggle," (Box-folder 77: 2)
    - "Fatal Illusions in the Horn of Africa,", 1991 (Box-folder 77: 3-8)
    - "Hope on the Horizon for Ethiopia,", 1991 (Box-folder 77: 9)
    - "Talking to Tyrants: Missions to Siad Barre and Mengistu Haile-Mariam, 1977-1978,", 1991 (Box-folder 77: 10)
    - "The United States and Ethiopia: Past, Present and Future,", 1991 (Box-folder 77: 11)
    - "Ethiopia," summary, 1991 January (Box-folder 77: 12)
    - Review of The Making of Economic Policy in Africa by Ravi Gulhati, 1991 January (Box-folder 77: 13)
    - "Starvation in a Potential Breadbasket,", 1991 February (Box-folder 77: 14)
    - "Ethiopia in 1990: The Revolution Unraveling,", 1991 March (Box-folder 77: 15)
    - "Conversation with Isaias Afewerki,", 1991 March 11 (Box-folder 77: 16)
    - "Eritrea: The Economic Challenge,", 1991 May (Box-folder 78: 1)
      Revision of the November 1990 article.
    - "U.S. Gets Results by Treading Softly in Ethiopia,", 1991 May (Box-folder 78: 2)
    - "Conversation with Meles Zenawi,", 1991 May 29 (Box-folder 78: 3)
    - "Recovery in the Horn of Africa,", 1991 May 30 (Box-folder 78: 4)
    - Interview of Paul Henze by unidentified correspondent, 1991 July (Box-folder 78: 5)
    - Review of Henze's book Horn of Africa: From War to Peace, 1991 August (Box-folder 78: 6)
    - "Tourism in Ethiopia: Observations and Recommendations,", 1991 August (Box-folder 78: 7)
    - "Africa in a Post-Communist World,", 1991 October (Box-folder 78: 8)
    - "Primacy of Economics for the Future of the Horn of Africa,", 1991 November (Box-folder 78: 9)
    - "Thoughts on the Formation and Operation of Political Parties in Ethiopia,", 1991 November (Box-folder 78: 10)
    - "The Horn of Africa: From Soviet Intervention to Soviet Irrelevance and Reassertion of American Influence,", 1991 December (Box-folder 78: 11)
    - "The Defeat of the Derg and the Establishment of New Governments in Ethiopia and Eritrea,", 1992 (Box-folder 78: 12)
    - "Journeys in Jirru,", 1992 (Box-folder 78: 13)
    - Review of Henze's book Horn of Africa: From War to Peace, 1992 January (Box-folder 78: 14)
    - "Ethiopia in Transition: Government and Law, A Report for the U.S. Institute of Peace,", 1992 February (Box-folder 78: 15)
    - "Journey to Massawa,", 1992 April (Box-folder 78: 16)
    - "Ethiopia: Prerequisites for Successful Political and Economic Development,", 1992 July 8 (Box-folder 78: 17)
    - "Ethnicity, Democracy and Federalism: Reflections on Ethiopia in mid-1992,", 1992 July 8 (Box-folder 78: 18)
    - "Democracy, Ethnicity and Development in Ethiopia: An Interview with Paul Henze,", 1992 August (Box-folder 78: 19)
    - List of Paul Henze's Ethiopia photographs, 1993 (Box-folder 78: 20)
    - "Movement Toward Modernization: A Century of Progress,", 1993 (Box-folder 78: 21)
    - "The Eritrean Independence Referendum: Diary of an Official Observer,", 1993 April (Box-folder 78: 22)
    - "Political Parties in Ethiopia's Future,", 1993 May (Box-folder 78: 23)
    - "Who 'Lost' Eritrea? What Has Been 'Lost?,'", 1993 May (Box-folder 78: 24)
    - "Three New Rock-Hewn Churches,", 1993 November (Box-folder 78: 25)
    - "The Monastery of Mertule Maryam: Questions and Speculations about Its Architecture and Ornamentation,", 1993 December (Box-folder 79: 1)
    - Open letter to Friends of Ethiopia, 1993 December (Box-folder 79: 2)
    - Book proposal on modern Ethiopia, 1994 (Box-folder 79: 3)
    - "Tourism in Ethiopia,", 1994 January (Box-folder 79: 4)
    - "Ethiopia and Eritrea in Transition: The Impact of Ethnicity on Politics and Development,", 1994 April (Box-folder 79: 5)
    - "Democratization in Ethiopia: An Interim Assessment,", 1994 May (Box-folder 79: 6)
    - Notes from Ambassador Irvin Hicks's briefing, 1994 May 16 (Box-folder 79: 7)
    - "Comments on the Ethiopian Draft Constitution of 1994,", 1994 August 6 (Box-folder 79: 8)
    - "Ethiopia: The Collapse of Communism and the Transition to Democracy: Adjustment to Eritrean Independence,", 1995 (Box-folder 79: 9)
    - "Ethiopia: The Fall of the Derg and the Beginning of Recovery under the EPRDF, March 1990-March 1992,", 1995 (Box-folder 79: 10)
    - "Adwa 1896: A Battle Crucial for Ethiopia's Future and of Worldwide Significance,", 1995-1996 (Box-folder 79: 11-12)
    - "Ethiopia in 1996: Preparing for the 21st Century," (Box-folder 79: 13)
    - "Crossroads of History: The Origins of Eritrea,", 1996 February 16 (Box-folder 79: 14)
    - "Meeting with Meles Zenawi,", 1996 March 26 (Box-folder 79: 15)
    - "American Scholarship on Ethiopia: Late Start, Substantial Output,", 1996 September (Box-folder 79: 16)
    - "Archaeology in Ethiopia: The Importance of the 'Medieval' Period,", 1997 (Box-folder 80: 1)
    - "Consolidation of Christianity in the Region of the Source of the Blue Nile: Traditions, History and Hypotheses,", 1997 (Box-folder 80: 2)
    - Research notes, 1997 (Box-folder 80: 3)
    - "Retrospective on Opposition to the Derg,", 1997 (Box-folder 80: 4)
    - "Traditional Ethiopia and Rural England: Persistence of Patterns in Rural Life,", 1997 (Box-folder 80: 5)
    - "Ethiopia and Africa: A Historical Excursus,", 1997 August (Box-folder 80: 6)
    - "Is Ethiopia Democratic? A Political Success Story,", 1998 (Box-folder 80: 7)
    - "Visit to Gunda Gunde,", 1998 February (Box-folder 80: 8)
    - "The Challenge of Historical and Cultural Preservation in Ethiopia,", 1998 April (Box-folder 80: 9)
    - "Democracy in Ethiopia: A Balance Sheet After Seven Years,", 1998 July (Box-folder 80: 10)
    - "New and Old in the Land of the Wagshums: Notes of Travels in Wag,", 1999 March (Box-folder 80: 11)
    - "Record of Conversations with Meles Zenawi,", 1999 March-April (Box-folder 80: 12)
    - "Georgia and Ethiopia: Parallels in the History and Culture of Two Ancient Countries,", 1999 April (Box-folder 80: 13)
    - "Public Relations Lessons of the Conflict with Eritrea,", 1999 June (Box-folder 80: 14)
    - "The Heart of Old Shoa,", 1999 October (Box-folder 80: 15)
    - "The Monastery of Mertule Maryam: Speculations about Its Architectural History,", 1999 October (Box-folder 80: 16)
    - "Genneta Maryam: A Historic Rock-Cut Church in Lasta,", 2000 (Box-folder 81: 1)
    - "Human Rights and the Ethio-Eritrean Border,", 2000 (Box-folder 81: 2)
    - Layers of Time, chapter 1, 2000 (Box-folder 81: 3)
      Includes reviews of the book.
    - Letter to the editor of The Washington Post, 2000 (Box-folder 81: 4)
    - "Eritrea's War Against Ethiopia: Causes and Effects, Reflections, Prescriptions,", 2000 January 18 (Box-folder 81: 5)
    - "Building an Ethiopian Lobby in the United States,", 2000 June 20 (Box-folder 81: 6)
    - "Challenge of Recovery from Communism: Comparison Between Ethiopia's and Other Countries' Experiences,", 2000 July 7 (Box-folder 81: 7)
    - "Conversation with Ethiopian Ambassador Berhane Gebre Christos,", 2001 (Box-folder 81: 8)
    - "Monasteries in Decline: Historical Objects in Danger,", 2001 October (Box-folder 81: 9)
    - "Report from Ethiopia,", 2002 (Box-folder 81: 10)
    - "Whither EPRDF? Whither Ethiopia? Contemplation of the Future,", 2002 (Box-folder 81: 11)
    - Interview of Henze, 2002 January (Box-folder 81: 12-13)
    - "Unexplored Aksumite Sites in Tigray,", 2002 April (Box-folder 81: 14-16)
      Includes photographs.
    - "Arsi Oromo Tomb Art: Its Evolution and Current Status,", 2002 December (Box-folder 81: 17-18)
      Includes photographs of Oromo tombs taken by Henze.
    - "The Monastery of Dabra Abbay,", 2003 (Box-folder 81: 19)
    - "Weynam Kidane Mehret: An Experience in Cultural Preservation,", 2003 (Box-folder 81: 20-22)
      Includes photographs taken by Henze.
    - "Meeting with Meles Zenawi,", 2003 July 17 (Box-folder 81: 23)
    - Interview with Henze conducted by The Reporter, 2003 July 23 (Box-folder 81: 24)
    - Review of Haile Selassie's War by Anthony Mockler, 2004 (Box-folder 82: 1)
    - "Human Rights and the Ethio-Eritrean Border,", 2004 January 13 (Box-folder 82: 2)
    - "Ethiopia 2004: Impressions of a Spring Visit,", 2004 April (Box-folder 82: 3)
    - "Protecting the Semyens: Four Decades of Effort,", 2004 September (Box-folder 82: 4)
    - "Democracy and Development: Lessons from Turkey's Experience Applicable to Ethiopia,", 2005 June (Box-folder 82: 5)
    - "Northeastern Tigray,", 2005 September (Box-folder 82: 6)
    - "Church and Monastery Treasures of Tigray,", 2005 October 4 (Box-folder 82: 7)
    - "Comments on Comments,", 2005 November (Box-folder 82: 8)
    - "Eritrea's Tragic Fate,", 2006 (Box-folder 82: 9)
    - "The Monastery of Dabra Abbay: Enda Abuna Samu'el,", 2006 (Box-folder 82: 10)
    - "Mysteries of Maryam Nazre,", 2006 (Box-folder 82: 11)
    - "Unexplored Aksumite Sites in Tigray--II,", 2006 (Box-folder 82: 12)
    - "Mifsas Bahri,", 2006 January 22 (Box-folder 82: 13)
    - Interview of Henze on potential sanctions against Ethiopia by unidentified correspondent, 2006 April 8 (Box-folder 82: 14)
    - "Bridges Over the Abbay,", 2006 May 28-31 (Box-folder 82: 15)
    - Letter to the editor of The Wall Street Journal, 2006 December 28 (Box-folder 82: 16)
    - "Ethiopia and Somalia,", 2006 December 30 (Box-folder 82: 17)
    - "After Mengistu,", 2007 (Box-folder 82: 18)
    - "Conferences, Consultations, Contacts in Washington and Abroad,", 2007 (Box-folder 82: 19)
    - "Ecotourism in Ethiopia,", 2007 (Box-folder 82: 20)
    - Foreword to Vertical Ethiopia by Majka Burhardt, 2007 (Box-folder 82: 21)
    - Interview of Henze conducted by Shama Books, 2007 (Box-folder 82: 22)
    - Introduction and postscript to third edition of Layers of Time, 2007 (Box-folder 82: 23)
    - "Introduction to Ethiopia in Mengistu's Final Years,", 2007 (Box-folder 82: 24)
    - "Meles Zenawi Comes to Washington,", 2007 (Box-folder 82: 25)
    - "Mengistu's Final Five Months,", 2007 (Box-folder 82: 26)
    - "Southward Progress of the EPRDF,", 2007 (Box-folder 82: 27)
    - "Exploring Unexcavated Aksumite and Pre-Aksumite Sites,", 2007 July (Box-folder 82: 28)
    - "Atsbi: Impressions and Speculations,", 2009 March 7 (Box-folder 82: 29)
    - "Whither EPRDF? Whither Ethiopia? Contemplation of the Future,", 2009 March (Box-folder 82: 30)
      Revision of 2002 article.
  - Writings by others, 1961-2008
    - A. Aseffa, 1988 (Box-folder 83: 1)
    - Abbink, Jon, 1991 (Box-folder 83: 2)
    - Abeba Tesfagiorgis, 1992 (Box-folder 83: 3-4)
    - Abebe Aemro Selassie, 1991 (Box-folder 83: 5)
    - Arriola, Leonardo, 2006 (Box-folder 83: 6)
    - Asfa-Wossen Asserate, 1993 (Box-folder 83: 7)
    - Asrat Woldeyes, circa 1992 (Box-folder 83: 8)
    - Bahru Zewde, 2007 (Box-folder 83: 9)
    - Balicka-Witakowska, Ewa, 1983 (Box-folder 83: 10)
    - Befekadu Degefe, 1980s (Box-folder 83: 11-14)
    - Belai Habte-Jesus, 1995 (Box-folder 83: 15)
    - Bereket Habte Selassie, 1997 (Box-folder 83: 16)
    - Burrowes, Robert D., circa 1991 (Box-folder 83: 17)
    - Campbell, Ian, 2008 (Box-folder 83: 18)
    - Carter, Jimmy, circa 1988 (Box-folder 83: 19)
    - Cheek, James, 1991 August (Box-folder 83: 20-21)
    - Chernetsov, S.P., 2001 (Box-folder 83: 22)
    - Chojnacki, Stanisław, 1963-2000 (Box-folder 84: 1-3)
    - Clapham, Christopher, 2000s (Box-folder 84: 4)
    - Cohen, Herman J., 1991 (Box-folder 84: 5)
    - Colburn, Forrest, 1986 (Box-folder 84: 6)
    - Connell, Dan, 2000s (Box-folder 84: 7)
    - Crocker, Chester, circa 1989 (Box-folder 84: 8)
    - Dagne, Theodore, 1991 (Box-folder 84: 9)
    - Daniel Haile, 1991 July (Box-folder 84: 10)
    - Dawit Wolde Giorgis, 1984 (Box-folder 84: 11)
    - Dereje Deressa, 1979, 1991 (Box-folder 84: 12-13)
    - Dessalegn Rahmato, 1987 May (Box-folder 84: 14-15)
    - Dewar, Michael, 2008 (Box-folder 84: 16)
    - Erlikh, Hagai, 1976, 1990s (Box-folder 85: 1-5)
    - Feleke Gedle Giorgis, 1979 (Box-folder 85: 6)
    - Fiala, Stanislas, 1988 (Box-folder 85: 7)
    - Garland, Elaine, 1979 (Box-folder 85: 8)
    - Getatchew Haile, 1990 (Box-folder 85: 9)
    - Getachew Kebreth, 1987, 2001 (Box-folder 85: 10-12)
    - Goshu Wolde, 1991 May 28 (Box-folder 85: 13)
    - H. Fullas Hailu, 1984 (Box-folder 86: 1)
    - Habtamu Mengistie, 2004 (Box-folder 86: 2)
    - Hagos G. Yesus, 1969 (Box-folder 86: 3)
    - Haley, Jim, 1993 (Box-folder 86: 4)
    - Henze, John, 1970s (Box-folder 86: 5)
    - Henze, Martha, 1997-2006 (Box-folder 86: 6-8)
    - Hickey, Tony, 2004 (Box-folder 86: 9)
    - Hodes, Richard, 1988 (Box-folder 86: 10)
    - Hodson, Arnold, undated (Box-folder 86: 11)
    - Isaias Afewerki, 1990 (Box-folder 86: 12)
      Interview of Isaias Afewerki by Steve Morrison, Gil Kapen and Jane Perlez.
    - Isaac, Ephraim, 1968 (Box-folder 86: 13)
    - Jordan, Robert Thayer, 1987 (Box-folder 86: 14)
    - Juel-Jensen, Bent, 1985 January (Box-folder 86: 15)
    - Kahsay Berhe, 1991 February (Box-folder 86: 16)
    - Kifle Wodajo, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 86: 17-18)
    - Krylov, A.B., 1985 (Box-folder 86: 19)
    - Krylova, G.A., 1989 (Box-folder 86: 20)
    - LeBel, Phillip, 1991 (Box-folder 87: 1)
    - Leroy, Jules, 1961 (Box-folder 87: 2)
    - Leslau, Wolf, 1990s (Box-folder 87: 3)
    - Levine, Donald N., 2008 (Box-folder 87: 4)
    - Long, David E., 1990s (Box-folder 87: 5)
    - Lyons, Terrence P., 1991 (Box-folder 87: 6)
    - Mesfin Wolde-Mariam, 1986, 2004 (Box-folder 87: 7-8)
    - Negede Gobezie, 1988 (Box-folder 87: 9)
    - Ottaway, David and Marina, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 87: 10-11)
    - Pankhurst, Richard, 1979 (Box-folder 87: 12)
    - Patman, Robert G., 1991 (Box-folder 87: 13)